<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on Daniccan Veerapandian</title>
    <link>https://daniccan.github.io/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on Daniccan Veerapandian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daniccan.github.io/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Permission Issues in Docker Volumes</title>
      <link>https://daniccan.github.io/posts/2020/fixing-permission-issues-in-docker-volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daniccan.github.io/posts/2020/fixing-permission-issues-in-docker-volumes/</guid>
      <description>Background I recently worked on a project which would help automate the build and test of Kibana plugins using Docker. You can read more about the project here.
The kibana-plugin-builder Docker container was initially developed to run as root and required a volume mount to access the source code of the plugin.
The Problem There were no issues with the above setup until 7.1.x version of Kibana. However, in 7.2.x, there was a new constraint introduced that Kibana cannot run as root and required its own user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Kibana Plugin Builds and Tests</title>
      <link>https://daniccan.github.io/posts/2020/automated-kibana-plugin-builds-and-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daniccan.github.io/posts/2020/automated-kibana-plugin-builds-and-tests/</guid>
      <description>Elasticsearch and Kibana Elasticsearch is a distributed search and analytics engine based on the Lucene library. It provides fast and flexible text-based searches on structured and unstructured data. Some of its major use cases include Logging &amp;amp; Monitoring, Big Data Analytics, Security Analytics, etc.
Kibana is the UI or presentation layer for Elasticsearch. It provides powerful visualizations for dashboards and reports along with the ability to run searches on Elasticsearch via REST calls.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
